Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And where are we going today, Erika?
今天我们聊什么，Erika？
To the pharmacy.
去药店。
All right, to the pharmacy or drugstore?
好的，去药店还是药房？
Yes.
是的。
Or also in British English, sometimes people say the chemist.
或者在英式英语中，有时人们会说chemist。
That's right.
没错。
So as you know, at the pharmacy you get medicine, but there are certain vocabulary words that
所以，如你所知，在药店你能买到药，但有一些与这个地方相关的词汇
are related to this place that we need to learn.
我们需要学习。
That's right.
没错。
And then some vocabulary about medicine and also some interesting phrases.
还有一些关于药物的词汇和一些有趣的短语。
So before we listen to the dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
所以在听对话之前，我们先看一下词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We're going to look at two words today that you'll hear in the dialogue.
今天我们要看两个你会在对话中听到的词。
And the first one, milligrams.
第一个是毫克。
Milligrams.
毫克。
Also, the abbreviation for this is MG.
它的缩写是MG。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a milligram is?
那么毫克是什么？
A hundredth of a gram.
一克的百分之一。
So there are 100 milligrams in a gram.
所以一克里有100毫克。
Exactly.
没错。
And it's very common to be used with medicine, right?
而且它常用于药物，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
We buy medicine in milligrams.
我们买药时用毫克计量。
Okay.
好的。
And what's our next word?
下一个词是什么？
Price check.
价格查询。
A price check.
Okay.
好的。
So at the pharmacy or at the supermarket, sometimes the cashier will ask for a price
所以在药店或超市，有时收银员会要求进行价格
check.
查询。
And that is the action of checking to find out the price.
那是查价的动作。
Okay.
好的。
So a price check.
所以是价格查询。
With this, I think we're ready now to listen to our dialogue for the first time.
这样，我觉得我们可以第一次听对话了。
And let's see what our shopper is buying at the pharmacy.
看看我们的顾客在药店买什么。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮你的？
Yes.
是的。
I need this prescription, please.
我需要这个处方。
Let's see.
让我看看。
Okay.
好的。
So 50 milligrams of Prozac.
所以是50毫克的百忧解。
Would you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
你想要胶囊还是片剂？
Capsules are fine.
胶囊就行。
Okay.
好的。
You should take one capsule three times a day.
你应该每天服用三次，每次一粒胶囊。
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach and also don't ever mix it with alcohol.
确保不要空腹服用，也不要与酒精混合。
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道。
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
这不是我第一次吃这个药。
Don't worry.
别担心。
I won't overdose.
我不会过量服用的。
Okay.
好的。
Anything else I can get you?
还需要别的吗？
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
Can I also get some eye drops and some condoms?
我能再买些眼药水和避孕套吗？
Sure.
当然。
Darn, condoms aren't registered in our system.
该死，避孕套没在我们的系统里登记。
Oh, well, that's okay.
哦，那没关系。
I'll get some later.
我以后再买。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Really, it's no problem.
真的，没问题。
Just hang on there a sec.
稍等一下。
Can I get a price check on Funtime's ribbed condoms, please?
能帮我查一下Funtime螺纹避孕套的价格吗？
Oh, no.
哦，不。
How embarrassing.
真尴尬。
A little bit embarrassing that she asked for a price check on these condoms, right?
她要求查这些避孕套的价格有点尴尬，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
It seems like every time you have to buy something embarrassing at the pharmacy, there's a million
每次你在药店买尴尬的东西时，好像总有无数
people watching you.
人在看着你。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
It never fails.
总是这样。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, let's take a look at some of those words that we were talking about related to medicine
好吧，我们来看看在“语言要点”中提到的与药物相关的
in Language Takeaway.
一些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
Well, the first word, a prescription.
第一个词是处方。
Prescription.
处方。
All right.
好的。
So what is a prescription?
那么什么是处方？
Well, a prescription is a note from your doctor explaining what medicine you need.
处方是医生开的说明你需要什么药的纸条。
So this note from your doctor is necessary to buy that medicine, right?
所以这张医生的纸条是买那种药必需的，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Prescription.
处方。
Well, this shopper was getting some medicine and, well, the chemist or the pharmacist asked
这个顾客在买药，药剂师问他是要胶囊还是
if he wanted it in capsules or tablets.
片剂。
So let's look at those two words.
所以我们来看看这两个词。
A capsule.
胶囊。
Capsule.
Now, a capsule is like a small tube, right?
胶囊像一个小管子，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
It's a form of a pill.
它是一种药丸的形式。
And it's shaped like a tube with the medicine inside.
形状像管子，里面装着药。
Inside.
里面。
Inside, inside inside, in plastic, right?
里面，里面，里面，在塑料里，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Now, you swallow the capsule.
你吞下胶囊。
Yep.
是的。
And the tablet?
那片剂呢？
Is like a pill that is round and flat.
是圆形扁平的药丸。
Okay.
好的。
So tablet and capsule.
所以片剂和胶囊。
Both are the same thing basically, but just different presentations.
基本上是一样的东西，只是不同的形式。
Different shapes.
不同的形状。
Yeah.
是的。
It's easier maybe for some people to swallow a capsule.
也许有些人更容易吞下胶囊。
You think so?
你这么觉得？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think so.
我觉得是。
Well, like-
嗯，就像——
Because sometimes tablets are a little bit like big circles and it's hard to swallow.
因为有时片剂有点大圆形，很难吞。
Yeah.
是的。
And I guess capsules are smoother.
我想胶囊更滑顺。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
But we're not pharmacists, so let's move on and focus on the language, which is what
但我们不是药剂师，所以继续关注语言，这才是
we do know about.
我们擅长的。
So the pharmacist warned the patient not to take too much medicine, right?
药剂师警告病人不要吃太多药，对吧？
Because he might overdose.
因为他可能会过量服用。
Overdose.
过量服用。
Okay, so to overdose, like you said...
好的，所以过量服用，就像你说的……
Is to take too much medicine and get really sick or even die.
是吃太多药，导致生病甚至死亡。
So if you overdose on medicine, it could be bad for you instead of good.
所以如果你过量服药，可能有害而不是有益。
Well, obviously very bad.
嗯，显然非常有害。
And what about our last word for today?
那今天的最后一个词呢？
Well, the shopper also asked for some eye drops.
顾客还买了眼药水。
Eye drops.
眼药水。
So this is medicine for your eyes.
这是用于眼睛的药。
Yeah, usually liquid, like water that you put in your eyes.
是的，通常是液体，像水一样滴进眼睛。
Okay.
好的。
So I think now with this medicine language clear, we can listen to our dialogue again,
所以我觉得现在这些药物词汇清楚了，我们可以再听一遍对话，
but it's going to be slowed down a little bit.
但这次会慢一点。
It'll help us understand these phrases just a little bit better.
这有助于我们更好地理解这些短语。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮你的？
Yes, I need this prescription, please.
是的，我需要这个处方。
Let's see.
让我看看。
Okay.
好的。
So, 50 milligrams of Prozac.
所以是50毫克的百忧解。
Would you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
你想要胶囊还是片剂？
Capsules are fine.
胶囊就行。
Okay.
好的。
You should take one capsule three times a day.
你应该每天服用三次，每次一粒胶囊。
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach.
确保不要空腹服用。
And also, don't ever mix it with alcohol.
还有，不要与酒精混合。
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道。
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
这不是我第一次吃这个药。
Don't worry.
别担心。
I won't overdose.
我不会过量服用的。
Okay.
好的。
Anything else I can get you?
还需要别的吗？
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
Can I get some eye drops and some condoms?
我能买些眼药水和避孕套吗？
Sure.
当然。
Darn condoms aren't registered in our system.
该死的避孕套没在我们的系统里登记。
Oh, well, that's okay.
哦，那没关系。
I'll get some later.
我以后再买。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Really, it's no problem.
真的，没问题。
Just hang on there a sec.
稍等一下。
Can I get a price check on Funtime's ribbed condoms, please?
能帮我查一下Funtime螺纹避孕套的价格吗？
Okay, so now it's time for us to take a look at some of the phrases that we saw in this
好的，现在是时候看看我们在“融会贯通”中看到的
dialogue in Putting It Together.
一些短语了。
Putting It Together.
融会贯通。
We're going to look at two phrases here and we're going to see how we can use them in
我们要看两个短语，看看如何在不同情境中使用
different situations.
它们。
The pharmacist warned, be sure not to take it on an empty stomach.
药剂师警告说：“确保不要空腹服用。”
Okay, so be sure not to.
好的，所以是“确保不要”。
Be sure not to.
确保不要。
What does he mean by this?
他这是什么意思？
He just means don't do this.
他只是说不要这样做。
Okay.
好的。
So don't take the medicine without eating.
所以不要不吃药就吃药。
We can mix it up a little bit.
我们可以稍微变化一下。
Why don't we listen to some examples of how we can use this in different situations.
我们听一些例子，看看如何在不同情境中使用它。
Example one.
例子一。
Be sure not to leave your bike outside or it will be stolen.
确保不要把自行车放在外面，否则会被偷。
Example two.
例子二。
Be sure not to forget your umbrella.
确保不要忘记带伞。
It's raining today.
今天下雨。
Example three.
例子三。
I told him to be sure not to do anything stupid, but he did.
我告诉他确保不要做任何蠢事，但他还是做了。
So Marco, why should we say be sure not to instead of don't?
那么Marco，为什么我们要说“确保不要”而不是“不要”？
I think don't sounds more like an order.
我觉得“不要”听起来更像命令。
Okay.
好的。
Very direct.
非常直接。
Maybe be sure not to is a little bit softer, a little bit more friendly.
也许“be sure not to”稍微柔和一点，更友好一些。
So be sure not to.
所以是“be sure not to”。
Now for our last phrase.
现在来看我们最后一个短语。
So the pharmacist in the end wanted to check for the price and he said, just hang on there
所以药剂师最后想查一下价格，他说，“just hang on there”
a sec.
a sec。
So that's interesting.
这挺有意思的。
Hang on.
Hang on。
Well, hang on.
嗯，Hang on。
What does he mean by hang on?
他说的“hang on”是什么意思？
He means wait.
他的意思是“等一等”。
Wait.
等一等。
It's an informal way of saying wait.
这是“等一等”的非正式说法。
Exactly.
没错。
It's also a little bit more friendly than just saying wait.
它也比直接说“等一等”更友好一些。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
And we can change the time a little bit, right?
我们还可以稍微改变一下时间长度，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So we can say hang on a second.
所以我们可以说“hang on a second”。
Or hang on a moment.
或者“hang on a moment”。
Hang on a minute.
“Hang on a minute”。
All right.
好的。
What about hang on an hour?
那“hang on an hour”呢？
Well, maybe if you're telling someone to wait for an hour, just hang on there for an hour.
嗯，如果你要告诉别人等一个小时，可以说“just hang on there for an hour”。
I'll be there soon.
我很快就到。
Yeah.
是的。
But I guess it's more common hang on a minute.
但我觉得更常见的是“hang on a minute”。
Right.
对。
Maybe for shorter periods of time.
可能用于较短的时间。
Okay.
好的。
So with these phrases, I think now we can use them in different circumstances, obviously
所以有了这些短语，我想我们现在可以在不同场合使用它们了，显然
not only in the pharmacy.
不仅仅是在药房里。
But let's listen to our dialogue for the last time.
但让我们最后听一遍对话。
Hello sir.
你好，先生。
How can I help you?
有什么能帮您的？
Yes.
是的。
I need this prescription, please.
我需要这张处方，谢谢。
Let's see.
让我看看。
Okay.
好的。
So 50 milligrams of Prozac.
所以是50毫克的百忧解。
Would you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
您想要胶囊还是片剂？
Capsules are fine.
胶囊就行。
Okay.
好的。
You should take one capsule three times a day.
您应该每天服用三次，每次一粒胶囊。
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach and also don't ever mix it with alcohol.
切记不要空腹服用，也千万不要和酒精一起服用。
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道。
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
这不是我第一次吃这个药了。
Don't worry.
别担心。
I won't overdose.
我不会过量服用的。
Okay.
好的。
Anything else I can get you?
还需要别的吗？
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
Can I also get some eye drops and some condoms?
能再给我一些眼药水和避孕套吗？
Sure.
当然。
Darn, condoms aren't registered in our system.
糟糕，避孕套没有录入我们的系统。
Oh, well, that's okay.
哦，那没关系。
I'll get some later.
我晚点再买。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Really, it's no problem.
真的，没问题。
Just hang on there a sec.
请稍等一下。
Can I get a price check on Funtimes Ribbed Condoms, please?
能帮我查一下Funtimes螺纹避孕套的价格吗？
Okay.
好的。
So with medicine, an interesting thing comes up, right?
所以关于药物，有一个有趣的地方，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A lot of people think that you eat medicine.
很多人认为“吃”药。
Okay.
好的。
Or drink medicine?
或者“喝”药？
Yeah.
是的。
But in English, you always take medicine.
但在英语中，你总是“take medicine”。
Always take medicine.
总是“take medicine”。
Yeah.
是的。
So you never can say, oh, I ate my medicine yesterday.
所以你永远不能说，“哦，我昨天吃了药”。
It always has to be, I took my medicine.
必须说，“我服了药”。
Okay.
好的。
So you take the capsules.
所以是“take the capsules”。
Exactly.
没错。
Or take the tablets.
或者“take the tablets”。
All right.
好的。
So you take medicine.
所以是“take medicine”。
Now, an interesting thing in the United States, for example, it's very hard to get medicine
现在，在美国有一个有趣的现象，比如，很难
without a prescription.
在没有处方的情况下买到药。
That's right.
没错。
So we always talk about prescription medicine and OTC medicine or over-the-counter medicine.
所以我们经常谈论处方药和非处方药（OTC）。
So over-the-counter medicine is?
那么非处方药是？
Is medicine you can just buy without that prescription or note from your doctor.
就是不需要医生处方或证明就能直接买的药。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, if you have a headache, you can go to the pharmacy and buy aspirin.
比如，如果你头疼，可以去药房买阿司匹林。
Yeah.
是的。
And that's over-the-counter medicine.
那就是非处方药。
But prescription medicine, you can't get it without the doctor's note.
但处方药，没有医生的证明就拿不到。
Yes.
是的。
And like you said, in America, you almost have to have a prescription for everything.
就像你说的，在美国，几乎什么都要处方。
Which is strange because people can overdose on aspirin.
这很奇怪，因为人们可能会过量服用阿司匹林。
So tell us how medicine and pharmacies work in your countries.
所以请告诉我们，在你们国家，药物和药房是怎么运作的。
And also if you have questions or comments, our website, EnglishPod.com is always open
另外，如果你有问题或评论，我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 随时开放
and ready for you.
欢迎你。
So thanks for downloading this lesson, you guys.
所以感谢你们下载这节课。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
We'll see you guys out there.
我们外面见。